Correct. The first way to split them does not help us at all.
没错 第一种分法完全没用
We ended up with very similar sets of
分割后的数据与原数据都包含相似的红点和蓝点
red and blue points and we learn nothing about the data.
对于我们了解数据没有帮助
The second way did a decent job.
第二种分法就比较好了
We managed to get most of the blue ones on
我们可以把大多数蓝点分在一边
one side and most of the red ones on the other side.
而把大多数红点分在另一边
So, now we know a bit more about it.
所以 我们对于数据有了一定了解
And the third one did fantastic.
第三种分法就更棒了
It managed to send all the blue points on
它把所有的蓝点分在一边
one side and all the red ones on the other side.
并把所有的红点分在另一边
Now we know a lot about our data.
现在 我们对于数据的了解就更多了
Actually, we'll learn how to calculate something called the information gain,
接下来 我们将学习如何计算信息增益
and it will be zero for the first splitting,
第一种分法的信息增益为 0
0.28 for the second, and one for the third one.
第二种为 0.28 第三种为 1
And the formula for information gain is very simple.
信息增益的计算公式很简单
It's just the change in entropy.
等于熵的变化值
Let me be more specific.
更具体点说
For every node in the Decision Tree,
在决策树中的每一个结点处
we can calculate the entropy of the data in the parent node.
我们可以计算父结点处数据的熵
And then, we calculate the entropies of the two children.
然后计算两个子结点的熵
The information gain is a difference between
父结点的熵与子结点熵平均值之间的差值
the entropy of the parent and the average entropy of the children.
即为信息增益
So, in our first example,
因此 在第二个例子中
you can calculate the entropy of the parent and its one.
我们计算得到其父结点的熵为 1
The entropy of each of the children is 0.72.
各子结点的熵为 0.72
So the average of the entropy of the children is actually 0.72.
故子结点的熵的平均值也为 0.72
Thus, the change in entropy is one minus 0.72, which is 0.28.
因此 熵的变化值为 1 减 0.72 即0.28
For this example, now, we can calculate the entropies of the children which are both one.
而在这个例子中 我们可以计算得到各自子结点的熵均为 1
Thus, the change in entropy is one minus one which is zero.
因此 熵的变化为 1 减 1 即 0
This is a terrible splitting because they gave us zero information.
这个分法很糟糕 因为它没有提供任何信息
And finally, in this example,
而在第三种分法中
the entropy of the children are both zero,
两个子结点的熵均为零
since as we saw,
正如我们所见
a set where the points are the same color has zero entropy.
一个集合中点的颜色一致时 其熵为 0
Thus, the information gain is one minus zero which is one.
因此 其信息增益为 1 减 0 即 1
This split gave us the largest information gain and as you can see,
这种分法给我们的信息增益最大
it is the best split because it managed to
它完美地将蓝点和红点分开
perfectly cut the data into the blue points and red points.
因此这是最好的分法
So, here's our summary. The three cuts with the values of information gain.
我们做一下总结 以下是三种分法以及其信息增益值
If the tree had to choose,
如果决策树必须做出选择
it would go for the third cut,
它将选择第三种分法
which is the one that gives it the largest amount of information gain.
因为第三种分法提供的信息增益最大